<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en, cn"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://bowenyi-umich.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://bowenyi-umich.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en, cn"/><updated>2024-06-24T20:43:55+00:00</updated><id>https://bowenyi-umich.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">Neural Networks</title><link href="https://bowenyi-umich.github.io/blog/2023/neural_networks/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Neural Networks"/><published>2023-12-10T01:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-10T01:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://bowenyi-umich.github.io/blog/2023/neural_networks</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bowenyi-umich.github.io/blog/2023/neural_networks/"><![CDATA[<p>Neural networks are a widely used algorithm in supervised learning, which involves labeled data. These networks take in inputs and produce a corresponding label.</p> <p>As the name suggests, a neural network consists of multiple neurons. Each neuron performs two tasks:</p> <ol> <li>It computes the linear combination of inputs from the previous layer using weights.</li> <li>It transforms this linear combination using an activation function.</li> </ol> <p>Training a neural network involves two steps: forward propagation and backward propagation. Here’s a simplified explanation of both procedures and how they contribute to training a neural network:</p> <ol> <li> <p>Initialize Weights and Biases: The weights and biases of the neural network are initially set to random values.</p> </li> <li> <p>Forward Propagation: The input data is passed through the network, resulting in an initial prediction.</p> </li> <li> <p>Calculate Loss: The difference between the network’s prediction and the actual output is calculated. This difference is often referred to as the loss or error. The goal is to minimize this error so that our prediction closely matches the expected label. To achieve this, we adjust the learnable parameters (weights and biases) in the next step: backward propagation. After each adjustment, our predicted label should get closer to the expected label. Remember, we are dealing with labeled data in supervised learning!</p> </li> <li> <p>Backward Propagation (Backpropagation): The error is then propagated back through the network. This involves calculating the gradient of the error with respect to the weights and biases. The gradient points in the direction of the steepest increase in the error.</p> </li> <li> <p>Update Weights and Biases: The weights and biases are then updated in the opposite direction of the gradient. This is achieved by subtracting the gradient of the weights and biases (multiplied by a learning rate) from the current weights and biases. This process is known as gradient descent.</p> </li> <li> <p>Iterate: Steps 2-5 are repeated for a number of iterations or until the network’s predictions are satisfactory.</p> </li> </ol> <p>The learning rate is a hyperparameter that determines the extent of adjustment to the weights and biases with each update. A smaller learning rate might slow down the learning process but increase its precision, while a larger learning rate might speed it up but decrease its accuracy.</p> <p>This process allows the neural network to learn from its mistakes, much like how humans learn from their experiences. Over time, this iterative process of forward propagation, loss calculation, backpropagation, and weight and bias updates enables the neural network to minimize the error of its predictions.</p> <p>For more information, you can refer to this blog article: <a href="https://developer.nvidia.com/blog/a-data-scientists-guide-to-gradient-descent-and-backpropagation-algorithms/">A Data Scientist’s Guide to Gradient Descent and Backpropagation Algorithms.</a>. Also, please make sure to check out these two discussion notes: <a href="https://umich-my.sharepoint.com/:b:/g/personal/bowenyi_umich_edu/EdvDNzOy65lDgObkMYGg7hgBImzrTPGlaSV0mzeAiwq7Pg?e=pvAq8O">Neural Networks</a> and <a href="https://umich-my.sharepoint.com/:b:/g/personal/bowenyi_umich_edu/EcwmM3MDDyxGi_YGvqRhiMEBUJwkoG4QTbfMB-Uyu2KjPw?e=TjUBEd">Convolutional Neural Networks</a> of EECS 445 at UMich for more details!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="ML/NLP"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A short explanation of neural networks]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Methodology to Do CS Research</title><link href="https://bowenyi-umich.github.io/blog/2023/research/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Methodology to Do CS Research"/><published>2023-12-10T01:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-10T01:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://bowenyi-umich.github.io/blog/2023/research</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bowenyi-umich.github.io/blog/2023/research/"><![CDATA[<p>Here’s an overview of how to do research in CS, referred from <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1703.04080.pdf">Hossein Hassani’s paper</a>:</p> <ol> <li> <p>Identify a Research Problem: The first step is to identify a problem that needs solving. This could be a gap in the current understanding, a new idea, or a practical issue that needs a computational solution.</p> </li> <li> <p>Literature Review: This involves reading and analyzing existing research related to the problem. The goal is to understand what has already been done, identify gaps, and determine how your research can contribute.</p> </li> <li> <p>Formulate a Hypothesis or Research Question: Based on the problem and literature review, you formulate a hypothesis (a proposed explanation) or a research question that your study aims to answer.</p> </li> <li> <p>Design the Study: This involves deciding on the research methods to use. In computer science, this could involve formal proof techniques, empirical methods, or a combination of both2. It could also involve designing and implementing a system or algorithm.</p> </li> <li> <p>Conduct the Research: This is where you carry out your study. It could involve running experiments, collecting and analyzing data, or proving theorems.</p> </li> <li> <p>Analyze the Results: After conducting the research, you analyze the results to see if they support your hypothesis or answer your research question.</p> </li> <li> <p>Draw Conclusions and Write the Research Paper: Based on your analysis, you draw conclusions about your research. You then write a research paper detailing your methods, findings, and conclusions.</p> </li> <li> <p>Peer Review and Publication: After writing your paper, it goes through a peer review process before it can be published. Other researchers in your field review your work to ensure it is of high quality.</p> </li> </ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Others"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here’s an overview of how to do research in CS, referred from Hossein Hassani’s paper: Identify a Research Problem: The first step is to identify a problem that needs solving. This could be a gap in the current understanding, a new idea, or a practical issue that needs a computational solution.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Wonderful Thanksgiving!</title><link href="https://bowenyi-umich.github.io/blog/2023/thanksgiving/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Wonderful Thanksgiving!"/><published>2023-11-28T04:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-28T04:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://bowenyi-umich.github.io/blog/2023/thanksgiving</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bowenyi-umich.github.io/blog/2023/thanksgiving/"><![CDATA[<p>I am composing this post on the inaugural snowy day in Ann Arbor this academic year. The weather outside is more picturesque than cold. As my reflection dances in the windowpanes, I delve into memories of the recent Thanksgiving break:</p> <p>For Thanksgiving 2024, I was honored to spend the holiday with my housemate’s family in Grand Rapids. It was the second city I had the good fortune to live in Michigan (the first being Ann Arbor).</p> <p>On the Tuesday preceding Thanksgiving, a kindly aunt offered me a ride to Grand Rapids. I was warmly welcomed by homemade Hunanese cuisine prepared by Mrs. Yang on my first night; a delightful surprise as the Yang family and I all hail from Hunan. The evocative flavors, redolent of my parents’ and grandmother’s cooking, eased my homesickness considerably, taking refuge in an invitingly decorated study room that served as my bedroom.</p> <p>On day two, I explored the sprawling, scenic community the family resided in, with easy access to parks, ponds, and trails. The spectacular nature and residential areas coexisted harmoniously, as evidenced by the wildlife I spotted during my afternoon walks. Interestingly, while Ann Arbor is renowned for its rich wildlife, Grand Rapids stood out for its harmonious human-nature coexistence. In the evening, Mr. Yang arranged a sumptuous dinner party where my classmates and I, all Hunanese, introduced two American guests to our spicy cuisine.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/IMG_0400.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="400px" height="400px" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Mrs. Deer :) </div> <p>The third day was Thanksgiving, and we spent the afternoon exploring Downtown Grand Rapids. The organization of the city was strikingly distinct from Downtown San Diego, which I had visited on a few occasions. The streets, deserted in observance of the holiday, were home to few homeless people, likely due to the cold. We enjoyed a walk along the river at the town center and visited a few significant landmarks, including Mr. Yang’s office, several museums and President Ford’s burial site (although these were closed).</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/IMG_0424.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="400px" height="400px" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/IMG_0425.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="400px" height="400px" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Selfie :D </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/IMG_0434.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="400px" height="400px" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/IMG_0444.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="400px" height="400px" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/IMG_0450.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="400px" height="400px" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Salmon passway (no fishing here!) </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/IMG_0466.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="400px" height="400px" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Oldest metal bridge in Michigan, built by an Ohio company sarcastically :D </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/IMG_0481.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="400px" height="400px" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/IMG_0488.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="400px" height="400px" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> The Amway headquarter </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/IMG_0509.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="400px" height="400px" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> First time see such bridges in real life, reminds me of "The Bridges of Madison County" </div> <p>Our return home at 5:00PM signaled the preparation of a lavish Thanksgiving dinner that featured an eclectic mix of traditional Hunan pork fried with chili, salmon, mussels, chicken, and lobster. We also welcomed a new guest, the erudite Uncle Liu, an alumnus of Peking University.</p> <p>BLACK FRIDAY signified the fourth day. Despite not having a specific shopping list, I joined the Yang family for an outlet mall visit to soak in the festive atmosphere. Mr. Yang intended to purchase a few items for his family in China, leading us to brave the early hours and long lines at various stores offering hefty discounts. Upon our departure at 1:00 PM, the outlet mall had amassed a mile-long queue of cars.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <iframe src="https://youtube.com/shorts/pG7fBijkfZc" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" width="auto" height="auto"/> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Our visit to an Outlets store </div> <p>On the fifth, also the second last day with the Yang family, Mr. Yang treated me and Frank, my housemate, to a barbeque experience. The smoked ribs, delectably reminiscent of La Rou (腊肉), a popular Hunan dish, were a culinary highlight.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/IMG_0540.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="400px" height="400px" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> First time having BBQ in the States :D </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/IMG_0541.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="400px" height="400px" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> The Yang family's puppy :D </div> <p>Finally, on Sunday, I bid the Yang family goodbye and returned home with the same kindly aunt, carrying a delicious trove of snacks and food she had packed for dinner. The Yangs are a paradigm of hospitality, their kindness contrasting my far-off home with comforting familiarity. Their story inspires me: Mr. Yang’s journey from a hardworking student and parent in Chengdu to fulfilling his American dream resonates with my own aspirations. This unforgettable Thanksgiving break with the Yangs not only enriched me culturally but also fortified my resolve to achieve my goals - not just for myself, but for everyone who supports and loves me. As my mother jokingly mentioned, my father looks forward to a friendly “drinking competition” with Mr. Yang when I secure a good job in the states - a milestone I eagerly anticipate and will work tirelessly towards.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/IMG_0544.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="400px" height="400px" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> I will see you again! </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="In Search of Lost Memories"/><category term="Personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The most wonderful and meaningful Thanksgiving I have ever had]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Happy 20th Birthday!</title><link href="https://bowenyi-umich.github.io/blog/2023/birthday/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Happy 20th Birthday!"/><published>2023-07-09T22:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-09T22:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://bowenyi-umich.github.io/blog/2023/birthday</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bowenyi-umich.github.io/blog/2023/birthday/"><![CDATA[<p>On July 9, 2023, I celebrated my 20th birthday, which stands out as one of the most joyous and fulfilling birthdays I’ve ever had. I had the pleasure of spending the entire day with my best friend, Mickey, who meticulously crafted a magnificent birthday cake for me. Words fall short in expressing my gratitude towards my cherished friend, who constantly radiates a comforting smile, spreads kindness and optimism, and ensures that I never feel alone, even when I’m miles away from home.</p> <p>The highlight of the day was the Forrest Gump “statue” that Mickey placed atop the birthday cake, a thoughtful gesture acknowledging my admiration for the movie character. This cake, symbolizing our profound friendship and carrying the best wishes, will forever hold a special place in my heart. It serves as a constant reminder to persevere and keep moving forward, just like Forrest Gump.</p> <p>Here’s to the longevity of my dreams and my enduring friendship with Mickey, the best there is!</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/20th-birthday.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="In Search of Memories"/><category term="Personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The most wonderful and meaningful birthday I have ever had]]></summary></entry></feed>